Previously on Transformers: Prime
在上一集里
It's as if the blood of Unicron the Destroyer
“破坏者”宇宙大帝之血
flows through my veins.
好像流遍了我浑身的经脉
Dark Energon?
可那会是黑暗能量吗？
It's so scarce as to be virtually non-existent.
那东西非常罕见 几乎搜索不到
Contact with civilians.
有生人介入
We're protecting them.
他们的安全由我们保护
Fetch me this Fowler.
把这个福勒给我带来
Tell me the location of the Autobot base.
告诉我汽车人基地的位置
It's an SOS.
是求救信号
- Scrap.
- 糟了
Rise, my army!
觉醒吧 我的战士们！
Behold, the power of Dark Energon!
请看 这就是传说中的…黑暗能量！
Megatron has desecrated the resting place of our fallen ancestors... and his own!
威震天亵渎了 我们共同先祖的长眠之地…他于心何忍！
Not even the dead are free from his war-mongering.
连死人也免不了被他推上战场
At last, symbiosis, I can feel it.
终于 我感受到和黑暗能量共生的妙处了
I possess complete control over my army.
我可以完全控制我的军队
Destroy them!
摧毁他们！
Optimus, if our combatants are already deceased,
擎天柱 如果我们的对手已经死过一次
How can we possibly defeat them?
我们能再“杀死”他们吗？
Ratchet, retreat!
救护车 撤退！
Bridge yourself back to base!
你先返回基地！
No, I shall stand with you, Optimus.
不 我要和你共进退 擎天柱
You may require a medic when this is over with.
战斗结束后 你可能需要治疗
I recommend dissection.
我建议 把他们解剖
The smaller the pieces, the better!
切得越碎越好！
Sound advice, old friend.
好主意 老朋友
I have mastered Dark Energon.
我已掌控了黑暗能量
When you fall, Optimus,
如果你战死 擎天柱
you too, shall join my army.
你也会成为我的部下
Get in, now!
上车 快！
Thanks, Bulkhead.
谢谢 隔板
Yea, thanks.
是啊 谢谢
What... what are you doing here?
你…你们怎么来了？
We were worried about Miko.
我们担心神子
Have you seen her?
你看到她了吗？
What's she look like?
她长什么样？
Everyone out.
全体下车
And this time, please, wait here!
这一次 拜托 在这儿等着！
Where's Miko?
神子在哪儿？
Miko?
神子？！
I heaved on your floor mats.
我吐在脚垫上了
Sorry! Ugh...
抱歉
Remind me never to do that again.
提醒我 以后别坐过山车了
Think they forgot about us?
他们把我们忘了吗？
I'm gonna heave again.
我又要吐了
Bring them to the brig.
把他们扔进监牢
Commander Starscream has keeping the other human there.
红蜘蛛指挥官把另一个人类也关在那儿
Bumblebee!
大黄蜂！
Appreciate you cleared the front door for us.
感谢你们清理了大门口
But storming the Decepticon warship was not on the activities list.
但进攻霸天虎战舰可不是娱乐活动
Tell me about it.
我们像在娱乐吗？
- Friendly! - Hello!
- 自己人！ - 还用说！
Brought the humans, huh?
竟然带人类出来打仗？
You try getting them to stay behind!
你来试试撇下他们看看！
We need to find Fowler and get these kids outta here.
我们得找到福勒 再把孩子们带出去
My dear Agent Fowler.
我亲爱的福勒探员
You do realize the Autobots have abandoned you.
你一定知道 汽车人已经把你抛弃了
I am the only one you can rely upon now.
我是你现在唯一的依靠
So, tell me what I want to know,
快把我想知道的告诉我
or...
否则…
Please, no more.
求你了 别这样
They're in secret government base.
他们在…政府的秘密基地
Go on.
说下去
Yes?
还有呢？
In the old steel mill,
那是个旧炼钢厂
was it under that carnival's fun house?
好像在嘉年华游乐园地下吧？
Someone find out what is going on out there!
去看看外面怎么回事！
is sapping our strength.
我们会吃不消的
We cannot falter now.
我们必须背水一战
Optimus! Eah...
擎天柱！
After all these years, Optimus,
这么多年过去了 擎天柱
still at the top of your game!
宝刀不老嘛！
My legion, finish them!
我的将士们 干掉他们！
Clear.
安全
Wait in here.
在这儿等着
They're slowing us down, and they're easy targets.
他们行动缓慢 容易受到攻击
They'll be alright in here,
只要他们不乱跑
as long as they stay put.
就不会有麻烦
That was intense.
刚才真是太吓人了
Was?
现在不吓人吗？
It's your fault that we're stuck in this intensity.
我们被卷进来 都是因为你
What were you thinking, Miko?
你是怎么想的 神子？
Did I ask you to follow me?
是我让你跟来的吗？
You wanted us to be a band.
是你要组建乐队的
Doesn't that usually mean "playing together"?
乐队不是应该“步调一致”吗？
Well, maybe I decided to go solo!!
那我要考虑单飞了！
Well, maybe I have some regard for your safety!
那我还是要关心你的安全！
Oh, I'm sorry, is your name Optimus?
噢 对不起 你也叫擎天柱吗？
You can leave my protection to Bulkhead, thank you very much!
有隔板保护我就够了 谢谢关心！
Stop it! Both of you!
别闹了！你们俩闭嘴！
Oh, hey hey hey, Raf, Raf, it's... it's ok.
噢 嘿嘿嘿 拉夫 拉夫 没事的
Yea, we're gonna be fine.
是啊 我们不会有事的
Our bots will come back for us.
我们的搭档会回来救我们的
Yea. They're gonna take us home.
是啊 他们会把我们送回家
How do you know?
你怎么知道？
Hey, Raf,
嘿 拉夫
what do you make of that?
你能看懂那个吗？
It's important.
是重要资料
Really important.
非常重要
Wake up, you pathetic lump of flesh!
睁开眼 你这可怜的肉团！
Well?
怎么了？！
Not so fast!
别太心急！
I wouldn't.
我不想动粗
Oh, but I MIGHT...
噢 我可没准儿…
We got to get this to Optimus.
必须把它交给擎天柱
How do you know it isn't just a recipe for space nachos?
说不定这是太空玉米片的食谱呢
I know math when I see it.
我一看就知道那是数学问题
And that is one serious equation.
那可是个信息量巨大的方程式
Can you... download it?
你可以…下载它吗？
I got a flash drive.
我有个闪存盘
But I don't see anywhere to plug it in.
但这里好像没有接口
This tech is way alien.
这东西太外星化了
Now, Agent Fowler and I will take our leave.
现在 我要带福勒探员先走一步
The evil says "yep!"
恶魔说 耶！
Miko, take a picture!
神子 拍张照片！
Great idea!
好主意！
Hey, you!
嘿 说你呐！
Not of that, of that!
不是它 是那个！
Go, go, go!
快 快 快！
I told you to stay put!
我说过 别乱跑！
I like pie.
我喜欢馅饼
Can we stop for pie?
可以去吃馅饼吗？
You found Fowler!
你们找到福勒了！
ROCK ON!
好哎！
Bravo, Optimus!
干得漂亮 擎天柱！
Though this is but a prelude.
这只是个序幕
You may wish to save your strength for the main event!
你最好为正戏保存一点实力！
You will not prevail, Megatron.
你不会得逞的 威震天
Not while energon still flows
除非我体内的能量枯竭！
Fit in, for this Dark Energon which flows through mine.
来日方长 我体内的黑暗能量也长流不息
If this wasn't Megatron's in game,
如果这还不算威震天的正戏
what is?
什么才算呢？
What happened to you guys anyway?
你们到底怎么了？
We engaged an army of undead Cybertronian warriors.
我们碰上了一队不死的塞博特恩战士
Zombies?
僵尸？
You fought zombies and I missed it?
你们打僵尸竟然不带我？
Bulkhead,
隔板
you exercised extremely poor judgement at allowing the humans to accompany you.
让人类跟你一起参加战斗 可不是个明智的决定
It won't happen again, Optimus,
不会有下次了 擎天柱
I promise.
我…我发誓
But it wasn't Bulkhead's fault.
那不关隔板的事
Miko, please!
神子 别说了！
And check it out.
你们看
Recon!
这才叫侦察！
It could be of importance to Megatron.
这对威震天来说可能是重要资料
Wow, Megatron's back?
喔 威震天回来了？
That's really bad news, right?
是个坏消息 对吧？
I... don't understand.
我…看不懂
Oops.
噢
That's the Con who'd tried to blow Raf away.
那个虎子想把拉夫炸飞
At least that's what it look like
他还没来得及动手
Miko, Raf was almost killed!
神子 拉夫差点没命
This isn't a game,
这可不是闹着玩的
when do you gonna get that through your fixed skull?
你那死脑袋什么时候才会明白？
Umm, we were all almost killed, Jack.
嗯 我们全都差点没命 杰克
You, me, Raf,
你 我 拉夫
even them!
还有他们！
Well, if this was just an average day with the Autobots,
如果和汽车人在一起 每天都有生命危险
then I don't wanna be a part of it.
那我不干了
Not any more.
彻底退出
Jack,
杰克
putting you in harm's way was never our intent.
我们从没想过让你去冒险
However, it is no longer the safety of you three that is at risk,
可是 生命悬于一线的不止是你们三个了
but the safety of all human kind.
而是全体人类
We will respect your decision if you wish to leave.
如果你们要离开 我们会尊重这个决定
No point in long good-byes. Here's the door.
别依依不舍了 门在这儿
Come on, Raf.
走吧 拉夫
I'll be ok, Jack. See you at school.
我要留下来 杰克 学校见
Sure thing.
好的
I know, you don't exist.
我知道 你们不存在
Don't make me hunt you down.
别逼我去抓你回来
Please, Lord Megatron, I meant no... Ah...
求你了 威震天陛下 我没料到…
I ordered you to await my command!
我告诉过你要等我的命令！
Instead, your mindless agenda resulted in the disabling of my ship!
可你干的蠢事弄垮了我的飞船！
And the delay of my plans!
还耽误了我的大事！
My intentions were pure, master.
我没别的想法 主人
I only wanted you to be rid of Optimus!
我只是想帮您除掉擎天柱！
No one rids me of Optimus Prime but me.
除了我 没人能除掉擎天柱
Do you understand,
你明白吗
do you?
明白吗？
Lord Megatron, I will make things right, I swear!
威震天陛下 我会处理好的 我发誓！
I know how to set your plans back on course!
我知道怎么能让您的计划回到正轨！
Explain, Starscream,
说清楚点 红蜘蛛
quickly.
别磨蹭
Now I understand why you had to rush home.
我现在明白了 你要赶回家修车
Don't you have something more exciting to do, Miko?
你没有更刺激的事可做吗 神子？
So, this is where you hang, huh?
看来 你就在这儿混日子 对吧？
Back home in Tokyo,
在东京老家的时候
I have loving parents and two purebred cats,
我有可爱的父母和两只纯种猫
Chi Chi and Ding Dong.
琪琪和叮当
I went to the best school, to piano lessons since I was three.
我去最好的学校 三岁就开始学钢琴
How nice for you.
挺好的嘛
No, how boring.
不 闷死了
It wasn't me.
那不是我想要的
Why do you think I jumped at the chance to transfer here?
当时要转学到这儿 我高兴得不得了
To Jasper, Navada,
因为内华达州贾斯帕是世界娱乐中心吗？
Yeah, well, the bros sure lied.
谁知道啊 唉 那些人撒谎
Piano lessons were starting to look pretty good, in fact.
学钢琴其实也挺有意思的
But then, the last couple of days happened.
然后 就发生了过去几天的事情
Do you have a point?
你到底想说什么？
You bet?
你觉得呢？
I saw what you did today,
你今天做的我都看见了
when you saved Raf,
你救了拉夫
when you came to save me.
还救了我
I've been raised to be responsible,
这些年我一直学着要负责任
to my schoolwork, to my mom, my job.
对功课 对妈妈 对工作负责任
Dude, hear me out.
哥们儿 听我说
You're no fry cook,
你不是厨子
you're a rock star.
你是摇滚明星
Stop pretending you're normal, Jack.
别装平凡了 杰克
You'll never fit in.
你绝对不是这种人
You were born to do so much more.
你注定要干些大事
Thanks, Miko.
谢谢你 神子
But I think normal suits me fine.
但我觉得平凡更适合我
It can't be.
这不可能
Optimus!
擎天柱！
These are engineering specs for a space-time vortex generator.
这些是时空漩涡发生器的技术资料
Megatron's building a Space Bridge,
威震天正在建造太空桥
if he hasn't already.
也许他已经建成了
The sooner he leaves, the better.
他走得越早越好
Bulkhead, a Space Bridge runs in two directions.
隔板 太空桥是个双向通道
Megatron may not be using it to leave Earth,
威震天可能不是要离开地球
but to bring through his conquering army.
而是用它召集军队
The main event Megatron referred to...
那就是威震天所谓的正戏吗？
But the only place Megatron could possibly recruit that many fallen warriors...
可是 唯一能让威震天召唤无数死人的地方是…
Precisely...
一点没错…
Cybertron.
塞博特恩